Mary van Kleeck Papers, 1849-1998
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE1849-1981, 5.75 linear ft.
  Family, Friends and associates, and the Sophia Smith Collection form the three subseries within this series. Correspondence may also include obituaries, newspaper clippings, photographs, memos, etc. There are many letters from her mother, Eliza Mayer van Kleeck in the Family subseries. The Friends and associates subseries contains the bulk of the material in this series. People with whom Mary van Kleeck exchanged significant correspondence and well-known individuals have their own folders, arranged alphabetically by last name and chronologically within each folder. Other individuals are included within the general correspondence for each letter of the alphabet. The general correspondence is also alphabetical by last name. Individuals' organizational affiliations are sometimes noted. In addition, correspondence is scattered throughout the collection. Especially significant amounts are in the organization files of the American Association of University Women, American Association of Social Workers, Hospites, International Industrial Relations Institute, National Research Council, National Women's Trade Union, and the U.S. Department of Labor. There is also correspondence with friends from van Kleeck's childhood and college days.
- SERIES III. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES1906-1961, 5.5 linear ft.
  The items in this series are divided into subseries denoting type of material and arranged chronologically within subseries. The bulk of the series is Articles and notes or typescripts of Speeches that Mary van Kleeck wrote and delivered throughout her career. Manuscripts and published versions of Speeches are filed together. The subseries includes conference papers, although occasionally a speech will be found within the files of the conference papers in SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES rather than within this series, especially if grouped with other peoples' speeches from a particular conference. Recurring topics include women and employment, social and economic planning, employee representation, social reform, unemployment, the Soviet Union, race relations, trade and labor unions, and social security. Four series of lectures are gathered together in a separate subseries, Lectures, at the end of Speeches. Other subseries include Monographs, Radio broadcasts, Interviews, Hearings (mostly on economic issues), Books reviewed by Mary van Kleeck, Reviews of Mary van Kleeck's books, Speaking engagement programs, Research notes, and Invitations to speak and write. The series contains writings co-authored by van Kleeck; it does not contain works to which she contributed only the introduction. Drafts or typescripts of van Kleeck's portion are included here, however.
- SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES1900-1961, 10.5 linear ft.
  This series contains some of Mary van Kleeck's research files, as well as topics that interested her personally. Items are arranged alphabetically by topic and chronologically within each topic. Newspaper clippings are a large proportion of the items in this series. Significant amounts of material can be found on civil liberties, the coal industry, countries, labor, and World War I and World War II. Edward Wieck performed much of the research contained in the files on the coal industry. Material about a few individuals, including Franklin D. Roosevelt, Alfred E. Smith, and Julius and Ethel Rosenberg, are included in this series. Materials about groups of individuals, such as African Americans, Italian Americans, and child labor are also included. Labor newspapers from this series are filed with the oversize materials.
- SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES 1897-1961, 27.25 linear ft.
  This series forms the bulk of the collection, and covers an extremely wide breadth of topics. Mary van Kleeck's personal level of involvement in organizations and conferences varied from intensely involved, as can be seen in the International Industrial Relations Institute files, to cursory, as is demonstrated by her materials on the American Management Association. Organizations and conferences are arranged in alphabetical order, and items are chronological within each folder. Most of the materials in publicity scrapbooks have been removed from their original binders, but are retained in their original order in folders. The Russell Sage Foundation is the most substantially documented organization in this series, and includes much of the research and many of the manuscripts produced by the Division of Industrial Studies during van Kleeck's forty-year career. Of special note are the materials on the Colorado Fuel and Iron Company, the Dutchess Bleachery, the Filene Store, the Rock Island Arsenal, and the Rocky Mountain Fuel Company. One can trace the evolution of these studies, from the field notes of the researchers, to the correspondence between the organizations and the staff of the Russell Stage Foundation, to the drafts of the reports to the final published copies. The final published versions of the reports are located in SERIES III. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES or SERIES VI. BOOKS FROM MARY VAN KLEECK'S LIBRARY. Information about unions, health care plans, and work councils of specific institutions was generated by the Russell Sage Foundation's study of employee representation. Other organizations that are substantially well-documented include Hospites, a refugee relocation organization that provided employment and financial assistance for social workers fleeing Nazi Germany in the 1930s; the American Civil Liberties Union; United States Department of Labor; and the International Industrial Relations Institute (IRI). Mary van Kleeck kept detailed records of the conferences sponsored by the IRI. Significant amounts of correspondence can be found in the organization records of the National Research Council (with Edith Abbott and Robert Yerkes) and the National Women's Trade Union League (with Elizabeth Christman, Mabel Leslie, and Rose Schneiderman).
- SERIES VI. BOOKS FROM VAN KLEECK'S LIBRARY1912-1961, 6.5 linear ft.
  This series contains books written by authors other than Mary van Kleeck and is arranged in alphabetical order by author's last name. (If there is no author, then monograph is listed in alphabetical order by title.) Van Kleeck wrote the introductions for several of the books and others contain copies of speeches that she gave. Many of these monographs were printed by organizations with which van Kleeck was closely associated, such as the Russell Sage Foundation, the National Conference of Social Work, and the International Industrial Relations Institute.
- SERIES VII. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS [Advance notice is required to hear or view materials without a use copy.]1929-1999, 2.25 linear ft.
  This series contains materials audio and video footage [collected or produced by Guy Alchon for a documentary he planned to make.] The documentary was never completed. Most of the series is composed of audiotapes and videotapes of oral history interviews. There is also some archival footage of Mary van Kleeck, a documentary on Central Casting, and a sample of the documentary. Some of the interviews have transcripts in SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS-Interviews and Recollections. Some items need use copies made before they can be played and will require advanced notice.
Contents List
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS1878-1985
  - Contents (Box 1, Folder 0)
  - Personal history
    - Biographical notes, resumes, etc. 1893-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
    - Drafts for biography in Notable American Womenundated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Places of residence: Photographs and descriptions 1904-92 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Testimony, Senate Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations 1953-54 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Passport applications 1953-58 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Will 1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Photographs 1883-1960s, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box 1, Folder 9-12)
    - Photographs taken by Mary van Kleeck
      - 1932-36 (Box 2)
      - Undated photographs (Box 3)
      - Identified negatives, [film, glass slides] (Box 4)
      - Unidentified rolls of negatives (Box 5)
      - Glass slides (Box 6)
    - Memorabilia 1894-1948, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Family and friends
    - Genealogy 1878-1990, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Obituaries and correspondence 1888-1951, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Charles Mayer van Kleeck: Saint Nicholas Society of the City of New York 1905-45, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Eliza Mayer van Kleeck: Bible 1862-1920 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Robert Boyd van Kleeck, Sr. 1833-52, 1897-1909, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 6-7)
    - Robert van Kleeck, Jr. 1923-24, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Brett-Teller Homestead 1906-1985, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Mary L. Fleddérus 1938-66 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Education
    - Flushing High School (Box 7)
      - General1896-1991 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Publications 1896-1901 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Mary van Kleeck's writing assignments 1987-1899 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Speeches 1900 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Grades 1896-1900 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Smith College, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--College Settlements Association]
      - Scrapbook, [fragile] (Box 8)
      - Entrance and housing materials 1899-1900 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Financial records 1899-1904, [see also Finances] (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Student Aid Society 1904-05 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Smith College Association of Christian Work 1903-06 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Memorabilia 1900-04, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Teacher's Bureau 1904-05 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Alumnae
        - General 1905-57 (Box 9, Folder 7)
        - Class of 1904 50th reunion, 1953-54 (Box 9, Folder 8)
        - Class of 1904 business 1955-57 (Box 9, Folder 9)
        - Alumnae Fund Committee 1912 (Box 9, Folder 10)
        - Smith Alumnae Quarterly: correspondence 1930-39 (Box 9, Folder 11)
        - Smith Alumnae Council 1957 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Columbia University
      - Class notes 1904-07 (Box 9, Folder 13-18)
      - Course offerings and outlines 1904-29 (Box 9, Folder 19)
      - Correspondence 1929 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Berkeley Divinity School 1924 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - St. Lawrence University 1938, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Finances, [see also Education--Smith College-Financial records]
    - Account books and receipts 1900-1915 (Box 10)
    - Account books and receipts 1916-21 (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
    - Checks 1904-17 (Box 11, Folder 4-8)
    - Checks 1918-21 (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
  - Daily activities record
    - College Settlement 1905 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Line-a-Day diaries 1917-26 (Box 12, Folder 5-6)
    - Files of daily activities1930-31, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box 12)
    - Notes on six weeks in the Soviet Union 1932 (Box 12, Folder 7-8)
  - Articles and newspaper clippings
    - Articles 1931-41 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper clippings 1899-1979, undated (Box 13, Folder 2-21)
  - Term papers and theses
    - "Mary van Kleeck and the Committee on Women's Work," by Margot Steinberg 1977 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - "Mary van Kleeck: An Intellectual Biography," by Joanne F. Keane 1977 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - "Mary van Kleeck: Case Study of a Social Reformer," by Lauren Hasselriis 1978 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Mary van Kleeck and Protective Legislation for Women: A Neglected Chapter in Progressive Reform," by Kathleen Lynn Wakefield 1979, [Note: This material cannot be photocopied.] (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) documents
    - General 1923-93 (Box 14, Folder 5-12)
    - Passports and passport hearing 1957-83 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Mary Fleddérus 1938-44, 1993-98 (Box 14, Folder 14-15)
  - Related archival collections
    - Edith and Grace Abbott Papers, University of Chicago (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Arthur Altmeyer oral history, Columbia University [fragment] (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America Records, Cornell University (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - American Association for Labor Legislation Papers, Cornell University (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - American Federation of Labor Records, State Historical Society of Wisconsin (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - John Carmody Papers, Franklin Delano Roosevelt Library (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Morris Cooke Papers, Franklin Delano Roosevelt Library (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Edward Costigan Papers, University of Colorado at Boulder (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Helen Gahagan Douglas oral history, Columbia University [fragment] (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Katherine Dreier Papers, Yale University and Museum of Modern Art (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - E. Franklin Frazier Papers, Howard University (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Lillian Gilbreth Papers, Purdue University (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - John Haynes Holmes Papers, Library of Congress (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Benjamin Huebsch Papers, Library of Congress (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Herbert Hoover Presidential Library (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - John A. Kingsbury Papers, Library of Congress (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Lewis L. Lorwin oral history, Columbia University [fragment] (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Mayer Family Papers, Maryland Historical Society (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Charles Merriam Papers, University of Chicago (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - National Archives (Box 16, Folder 4-5)
    - National Council of American Soviet Friendship Collection, New York University (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - National Interracial Conference, Howard University (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Otto and Marie Neurath Isotype Collection, University of Reading (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Frances Perkins oral history, Columbia University [fragment] (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Josephine Roche Papers, University of Colorado at Boulder (Box 16, Folder 10-13)
    - Eleanor Roosevelt Papers, Franklin Delano Roosevelt Library (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Edward A. Ross Papers, State Historical Society of Wisconsin (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Rockefeller Family Archives: Office of Messieurs Rockefeller, Rockefeller Archive Center (Box 16, Folder 16-18)
    - Russell Sage Foundation Records, Rockefeller Archive Center (Box 16, Folder 19-25)
    - Russell Sage Foundation Records, Rockefeller Archive Center (Box 17)
    - Russell Sage Foundation Records, Rockefeller Archive Center (Box 18, Folder 1-5)
    - Russell Sage Foundation Records, State Historical Society of Wisconsin (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Sisterhood of the Companionship of the Holy Cross (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Smith, Edwin Papers, Cornell University (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Society of the Catholic Commonwealth (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Ida Tarbell Papers, Allegheny College (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - University of Chicago Press Records, University of Chicago (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Lawrence Veiller oral history, Columbia University [fragment] (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Robert F. Wagner Papers, Georgetown University (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Industrial Research Collection, Wayne State University (Box 18, Folder 14-39)
    - Robert M. Yerkes Papers, Yale University (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Recollections and interviews with Guy Alchon re: Mary van Kleeck, [see also SERIES VII. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS]
    - Breines, Nesi and Simon 1989 (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
    - Boudin, Leonard 1989 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Cook, Alice 1991 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Fisher, Jacob (Jack) 1989 (Box 19, Folder 5-6)
    - Fleddérus, J. Dyck 1989 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Flexner, Eleanor 1989 (Box 19, Folder 8-9)
    - Grierson, Margaret 1989 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Hauessler, Dorothy (Dottie) 1990 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Hook, Sidney 1989 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Peters, Margaret 1993 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Roberts, Barbara 1990 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Slayton, Frieda and Sidney 1992 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Tiger, Edith 1989 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Van Kleeck, Clara 1990 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Voss, Johtje 1990 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Ware, Caroline 1989 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Written correspondence with Guy Alchon re: MvK
      - Fleddérus, J. Dyck 1989 (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - Foner, Philip S. 1989 (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - Grierson, Margaret 1989-92 (Box 19, Folder 22)
      - Keyserling, Mary Dublin 1989 (Box 19, Folder 23)
      - Neurath, Paul 1988-93 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Interview photos 1992 (Box 19, Folder 25)
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE1849-1981
  - Family
    - Bradford, Jane Mayer, cousin 1894-1904 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Bradford, Thomas Kell, cousin 1894-95 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Bruce, Katherine, cousin 1947-54 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Dionne, Elise Van Kleeck, sister 1890-1926 (Box 20, Folder 4-5)
    - Dionne, Leo Van Kleeck, nephew 1926-34 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Roberts, Barbara Bruce Stevens, cousin 1953-62 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Van Kleeck, Charles, brother 1891-1904, 1933-51, undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Van Kleeck, Eliza Mayer, mother 1891- Jun 1901 (Box 20, Folder 9-14)
    - Van Kleeck, Eliza Mayer, motherSep 1901-1903 (Box 21)
    - Van Kleeck, Eliza Mayer, mother1904-08, undated (Box 22, Folder 1-7)
    - Van Kleeck, Robert Boyd, father 1888 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Van Kleeck, Robert (Bob), brother 1891-1905 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Other family 1892-1910, 1949, undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Friends and associates
    - A 1903-40 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Abbott, Constance, Smith College, Class of 1904, 1903-05 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Abbott, Edith 1924, undated, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--National Research Council--Committee on Scientific Problems of Human Migration] (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Alfred, Helen 1956 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Altschuler, Michael 1931-36 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Ameringer, Oscar 1931-34 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Anderson, Mary 1923-38, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--National Conference of Social Work; U.S. Department of Labor---Women's Bureau; Oversize Materials] (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Andree, M., Bryn Mawr College 1930-37 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Andrews, John B., American Association for Labor Administration 1924-36 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Anthony, Susan Brownell II (1916- ), [see SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--International Women's Conference, 1945] (Box 23)
    - Arrowsmith, Mary N., American Red Cross 1922 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Atkinson, Henry A., Universal Conference on the Church of Christ on Life and Work 1922-25 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - B 1903-56 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Barkley, Mabel, Smith College, Class of 1904, 1904-05, 1935 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Barnes, Harry Elmer 1932-35 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Barteco, Edna 1891-93 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Beard, Charles and Mary Ritter 1935-58 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Beisser, Paul 1926-27 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Bennett, E. Howard 1927 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Berridge, William A. 1923-24 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Bingham, Walter V. 1928-38 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Blakenhorn, Mary, Consumer's League of New York 1927, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Bond, May A. 1929 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Bogdanov, Peter A. 1930-35 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Bogue, Anna T. 1936-40 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Bowers, Glenn A. 1927-38 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Boyd, D. Knickerbocker, Russell Sage Foundation 1934-39 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Boyert, Muriel 1894-97 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Breines, Simon 1936-38 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Bresee, Anna 1891 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Brett, Suzanne Ashley 1928-30 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Bridges, Frances Atkinson, Young Women's Christian Association 1903 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Brown, Nell, Smith College, Class of 1906, 1903-05, undated (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Bruére, Henry, Department of Labor 1929-30 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Bunche, Ralph 1933-35, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Burnham, Sophia Lord, Smith College, Class of 19041905 (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Burns, C. Delisle 1930-31 (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - C 1900-05, 1922-49 (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Carmody, John M. 1929-40 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - Carner, Lucy P., Young Women's Christian Association 1924-25 (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Carr, Charlotte E., Bureau of Women In Industry, Department of Labor 1925-29 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Carrillo, Alejandro 1938-40 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Carter, Edward C., Institute of Pacific Relations 1923-31 (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Chaddock, Robert E., American Statistical Association 1925 (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Chalufour, Aline 1941 (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - Chamberlain, Joseph P. 1931-35 (Box 23, Folder 39)
    - Chambers, Clarke A. 1971 (Box 23, Folder 40)
    - Chambless, Edgar 1932-33 (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - Chattopadhyaya, Kamaladevi [see Kmaladevi, Mme.]
    - Cheyney, Alice S., International Labor Office 1930 (Box 23, Folder 42)
    - Christman, Elizabeth, [see SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--National Women's Trade Union League] (Box 23)
    - Choate, Helen, Smith College, Class of 1904, 1903-05 (Box 23, Folder 43)
    - Claghorn, Kate H., New York School of Social Work 1926-36 (Box 23, Folder 44)
    - Clark, Earle, Russell Sage Foundation, [see SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Russell Sage Foundation-General--Correspondence] (Box 23)
    - Coit, Eleanor, Young Women's Christian Association 1924-36 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Colvin, Fred H.1933-42 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Contreras, Carlos 1938-40 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Cooke, Morris L., War Industries Board 1917-40 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Cornick, R. L. 1921, 1931 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Cravath, Paul 1933 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Crawford, Leslie, Smith College, Class of 1904, 1903-05 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - D 1922-42, undated (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Dana, Elizabeth, Smith College, Class of 19041905 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - DeKock, Jules, International Industrial Relations Institute 1938-44 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - de Schweinitz, Dorothea 1922-47 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Dewey, John 1928-34 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Dingman, Mary A., Young Women's Christian Association 1922-27 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Dodd, Marian Elsa, Smith College, Class of 19061903-05, undated (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Donald, W. J., American Management Association 1926-29 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Douglas, Dorothy 1935-38 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Dreier, Mary E. 1923-24 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Duchene, Gabrielle 1938 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - E 1894-1905, 1921-61 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Easton, Mary, Christian Association of Wellesley College 1903-04 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Eckenberger, Babette 1939 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Eddy, Harriet 1933-46 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Edelman, John W., American Federation of Full Fashioned Hosiery Workers 1932-33 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Ehrler, Hazel B. 1924, 1942 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Eldridge, Florence M. 1928-29 (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Emery, Andrée M. 1932 (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - Erskine, Lilian 1924 (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - F 1901, 1921-50 (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - Fairchild, Henry P., National Research Council 1923-30 (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Fairchild, Mildred, Bryn Mawr College 1933-38 (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Filene, A. Lincoln, [see SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Russell Sage Foundation--Department of Industrial Studies--Filene Store] (Box 24)
    - Firth, Norman C. 1930-33 (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - Fitch, John A., New York School of Social Work 1921-34 (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - Fleddérus, Mary L.
      - Mary van Kleeck 1925-29 (Box 24, Folder 33-35)
      - Mary van Kleeck 1930- (Box 25, Folder 1-10)
      - Dr. Meyer zu Schwabetissen 1930-31 (Box 25, Folder 11)
      - Others 1926-55 (Box 25, Folder 12-13)
      - Re: Visa 1937 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Fleisher, Alexander 1934-42 (Box 25, Folder 15)